When it comes to AI, everything's
probabilistic. But before AI and AI
agents, we were really used to
deterministic code. We can predict and
expect how it will behave, but that's
not the case anymore. So, by doing
evals, we are able to start making those
statistical judgments about how the
model is behaving, the agent is
behaving.
>> How do we make LLMs more predictable to
be able to say, yes, I know where to get
that information from? How do we get the
answers, the evals, highest?
>> Well, it's all about context, Simon. Of
course it is. Of course it is. So, what
Tesselo did is we launched something
that we call the Tesselo Registry. That
is a collection of more than 10,000, we
call them tiles. So, tiles are they're
collection of context. And in this case,
they have context about libraries. And
what we found is that it has better
abstraction adherence.
>> What were the results? Using Tesselo
tiles, on average, showed 35% higher
abstraction adherence, which was even
higher for newer libraries. There we saw
50% improvement.
[Music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So, whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So, if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode.
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI Native Dev. My name is Simon
Maple, and joining me today is Maria
Goranova, who is a member of technical
staff
at
in the AI engineering team at Tesselo.
Maria, welcome. And we're in the London
office, of course, in in Tesselo HQ. So,
we can have a nice face-to-face chat.
Maria, how are you? I'm good, thank you.
I'm very excited to be here, Simon.
Thank you for having me.
>> Longtime listener, first-time caller,
right?
>> Yeah.
Well, today, well, Maria, you were part
of a team that that built up wrote a
report and some findings in and around
well, basically a bunch of evals that is
testing how good coding agents can be
with and without various contexts at,
you know, performing certain coding
tasks. We're going to dig into that and
show some really interesting
information about when agent coding
agents can provide solid results versus
kind of like a little bit scrappier, not
sure about the the quality of those
results. So, really interesting deep
data coming up.
But first, who is Maria? Tell tell us a
little bit about yourself, Maria. Yeah,
sure.
Well, as you said, I'm a member of
technical staff here at Tesselo in the
AI engineering team.
Before that, I
had PhD from University of Edinburgh
in data science and machine learning.
And then I moved to
industry research, firstly at Twitter
back when it was still Twitter. It's
still is Twitter. Come on.
In in our hearts, it's still Twitter.
Yeah, well, I no comment.
>> Yeah, yeah.
And after that,
I was in a few other startups before
joining Tesselo. Awesome. Awesome.
From the AI engineering point of view,
what what what drives you into the into
the into the wonderful space of machine
learning and LLMs? What what what's your
passion around there? Good question. I
think I've always been passionate about
this intersection between programming
and logic and machine learning and data.
So, my PhD was kind of in in that space.
Even before that, some projects that I
did were in that space. So, I've always
been really keen on this, and then I
stumbled on Tesselo. I was like, wow,
like
these guys are really doing something,
and I want to be part of it. I think it
really matches like what my journey is
so far. Yeah. Yeah, wonderful.
>> So, that's what excites me. Wonderful.
So, let's talk a little bit about the
report.
So, yeah, there were a number of people.
So, there was yourself. Who else was on
the report? Max.
Um Who we had on the podcast just a
couple of weeks ago as well, which is
cool. Max,
he never sleeps.
He does so much work. So, there is Max,
there is Rob, and there is Drew, and
myself. So, that's the four of us
did this report, did a lot of work on
different evaluations. We actually have,
you know, more things cooking. So,
we're very excited for
follow-ups. Yeah, and I know certainly
within the within the Tesselo
organization, whenever when, you know,
we always love the AI engineering team
doing a whole bunch of this research cuz
we find such amazing kind of like little
gems and learnings from this.
And and it's, you know, one of the
things about LLMs just being so
non-deterministic is we have these
experiences, we have these anecdotal
experiences. And people will recognize
them when we when we say, oh yeah, the
LLM did this. Someone will typically a
user of an agent will typically say, oh
yeah, yeah, I saw I saw that. Yeah, I've
I've I've experienced that before. But
it's hard to actually understand, well,
what is the pain though? What, you know,
how bad is it? And I think one of the
things that I love that, you know, your
team and you you and the rest of the
team do
is with these with this with this
research, you kind of like go a little
bit deeper, and you kind of like show
the real pain. You know, what what what
are the problems? What are the
capabilities? And and let's and let's do
this. So,
with this report and with this
and it's out on the Tesselo AI blog, we
can we can share some links in the in
the show notes and things like that.
What are the what are the problems then
that this report is trying to discover
the I guess the scope of the depth of
what are the what are the key challenges
to agentic coding? Wow, that is a big
question.
Very big question.
Um
Thank you for asking. I think I find
this report and the work we did on this
very very interesting because I think it
it really hits on something that to me
is fundamental
when it comes to programming and and
software engineering, and that is
abstraction. It is
I feel software is really built on
abstractions that kind of get more and
more high-level, like a troshka, right?
Everything is is built from, you know,
the machine code at the very bottom, and
then you have higher and higher level
APIs.
And I think this is this is really
fundamental when it comes to software,
and I don't believe that it will change
or that it should change when it comes
to AI agents.
And the reason for that is that
I mean, yeah, sure, an AI agent can
generate everything from scratch. Can
generate machine machine codes from
scratch.
But does it make sense for it to
regenerate it every time and and never
use any existing abstractions that are
already out there? This sounds very
expensive, right?
Um
So,
thinking of this abstraction, one thing
that I personally observed with AI
agents that really annoys me is that
when I use them and ask them to write
some sort of code, they very often would
just
implement everything from scratch, not
use any libraries, or even if I tell
them to use a library, they're not going
to use it very well. I will have to like
really micromanage how they use it. Um
and it's kind of
sometimes sometimes that's fine.
Sometimes you just don't care. Sometimes
you just want to generate code from
scratch. But sometimes you really care
because
libraries are they have been optimized,
they are very performant, right?
Um they
they help with saving cost, saving time,
things like this.
>> More trusted as well, I suppose, cuz
they're out in the wild, everyone's
using them. People can, you know, come
in and and have expectations of how
things work.
>> Exactly. Exactly. And it's it's also,
you know, we're still at the stage that
maybe that's not going to be the case
one day, but right now we're still at
the stage that we're collaborating with
the agent. So, we still want to
understand that code or at least to some
extent be able to
work with it, right?
Um so, there are many many factors
there. I think it's it's a very
important problem.
One thing we were thinking about
we can do with with libraries and just
helping the agent use libraries more
effectively
is if we if we can firstly evaluate how
well it's using them, right? Because if
we want to improve this,
the first step is we have to be able to
measure it. We have to be able to
evaluate it. And unfortunately, to best
of our knowledge, there is not that
many, if any, benchmarks out there
existing that
touch on this. A lot of the benchmarks
that that are for coding, they have to
do with functional correctness. They
evaluate maybe based on some tests or
something like this. So, they evaluate
the behavior of the program.
>> Like a squee bench or a tea bench or
something like that.
>> Exactly. Exactly. And and you know, that
is
that is very useful
and shows us that the code works. But it
it misses exactly this problem of
reusability reusability of libraries. Um
so, that's why we created this
evaluation framework that
generates data that
really touches on the abstractions and
how well the agent is adhering to those
abstractions of a particular library,
and I go more in more in more details.
Yeah. And it's very interesting cuz I
think a lot of the I would say the
majority of the cases, probably, people
aren't building from scratch
necessarily. They're trying to use AI
agents to to
adapt or change their existing
applications. I'm sure there are plenty
of greenfield projects out there as
well, but in a in a for an organization,
you're trying to you're trying to work
out how you can do your day job quicker.
And a developer is 95% of the time in
their own code base working on on, you
know, small fixes, new features, etc.,
etc. So,
in that case, Uh, you want you know, the
agent is going to not just decide to use
certain libraries, it's going to have to
use certain libraries cuz that's what's
already in the in the existing uh in the
in the existing application. So,
Exactly. So, getting an agent to really
understand and code well against that
open source library is super super
important cuz it needs to do it. There's
a you you don't want it to all of a
sudden start building in its own way uh
because we as humans then have to start
reading this and going, "Well, why is it
building Why is it building everything
for itself versus just using these
libraries that we already import?" Um
Now, you mentioned evals and I I you
know, I can't go any longer than 5 to 10
minutes talking to someone from the AI
engineering team without them saying the
word eval. I'm sure I'm sure you you
must say that like a thousand times a
day or something like that.
>> think about this all the time.
>> It's Yeah, you dream about evals and you
Yeah.
It's Yeah, absolutely, we do. And and
and I think it is
uh
we think about this a lot.
>> What Why Why are evals so important?
Excellent question.
I think when it comes to AI,
everything everything's probabilistic,
right? We're before before AI and AI
agents, we're really used to
deterministic codes, right? We're
writing We're working with programs that
are deterministic. We know what the
output is when you we give it certain
input and so on. Uh we can test it. We
we
kind of we can predict and expect how it
will behave.
But that's not the case anymore. Um this
just not the case when it comes to
machine learning. Um
So,
it is very dangerous if we look at that
isolated example that works or doesn't
work and then make judgments on this. Um
so,
it is dangerous because then we're going
to make decisions about a product or a
feature or even our just day-to-day
workflow
um that are based on this one isolated
example that is just an anecdote. Yes.
And it it's not reflective of the
average. It's not the reflective of the
population.
So, by doing evals, which involves
really
doing it on many examples on a
population, then we are able to start
making those statistical judgments about
how the the model is behaving, the agent
is behaving, or um whatever tool we're
using is behaving. So, it's not just
about the correctness
of an agent, it's about how often that
agent will do the right thing. Yes,
because it's never going to be Yeah,
well, never say never, but I do
It's never statistically it's never
going to be 100% correct on any
anything. If you make it 100% correct on
a data set, you've likely are running
into overfitting issues. You're likely
not generalizing beyond that data set
that you're evaluating it on.
Um so, it is it's very important for us
to work with
evals that actually statistically
measure how well uh we're doing on a
population.
And there are of course many different
things that affect that number um
or all that eval score.
Well, one of which is the model itself,
the underlying model, how good the the
LLM is at being able to perform that
task. But of course, there are a bunch
of other things um such as the prompt
you use, the context you provide, and
things like that that you know, that
give the LLM a better chance of success.
What um We'll jump into that in a little
bit more depth. In terms of the eval,
what is the What is What are your evals
which look like for this for for this
report that we that we released?
>> Yeah, good question. So, what we did was
we um generated a data set, an
evaluation data set, Yeah. that consists
of pairs of a question, a coding
question,
and uh a criteria for evaluation.
But these questions, they're not just
they don't come from TeenAger. We
actually take a an existing library,
open source library,
and we use an agent to analyze this
library and then generate the question
based on the real API of this library,
both the question and the evaluation
criteria.
Um and we focus on questions
um that have to do with the So, the
coding task, the nature of the coding
task is that
it tries to evaluate someone's a
person's or or an agent's ability to use
a library efficiently and correctly.
Um so, it's less
you know, the typical coding tasks that
agents are used to are sort of like lead
code style, you know,
uh like um implement from scratch,
something like breadth-first search, or
that sort of task. This is not it. This
is more of a Oh, you have Pydantic.
Yeah.
>> Pydantic Python library.
Um now, use Pydantic to
generate that sort of class with that
sort of validation, you know. Um so,
it's it's more about it's more focused
on using the library.
>> Yeah.
Um So, yes, so that's the data set. And
then we um in order to evaluate a
method, we
ask it to solve that question. And then
separately, we use an agent as a judge
to uh evaluate the solution based on the
criteria that we previously generated.
>> Right. Right. Okay.
>> So, and the criteria is all about how
the API was used. Gorgeous. So, So, your
tests are twofold then. Your tests are
essentially, this is the challenge, and
then this is what I expect. This is how
your criteria is. This is how I expect a
correct solution to kind of like, you
know, it needs to use this library. It
needs to use this method on the library,
perhaps. It needs to pass this
information. And then we need to be able
to see this kind of outcome. So, it
still allows the the LLM to be creative
in whatever ways it wants to Absolutely.
>> code it, but it needs to hit those
several things which pardon me It needs
to hit those several things which um
which which require that correct use of
the library. Um Okay. What What are the
So, when things go good, they go good,
you get a pass. When things go bad, what
are the kind of things that we're
looking for? I can I can
already guess things like, you know,
that hallucination of the API that
doesn't exist, maybe very often because
it's actually picking the wrong version
of the API.
I- I- Is that a common thing? What What
What What are the things that we look
for when in failures?
Yeah, um so,
yeah, what you mentioned with the
versions happens uh for sure. Pydantic
actually, that I mentioned already, is a
good example of this because uh Pydantic
version two is quite different to
Pydantic version version one, and LLMs
often confuse it.
Um
But also, we have I think there is a
more fundamental problem, which is uh
new or or private libraries, right?
Things that might not be in the training
in the pre-training data of uh the LLM.
So, there is no preexisting knowledge
about this. Um And then suddenly,
you're asked to use this library, but
you don't know anything about it. So,
the If it's an agent, so if if it's an
LLM, it's just going to hallucinate. If
it's an agent, it might do web search,
it might read documentation, and so on.
But this is quite expensive, quite a
lengthy process, and it might not find
what it needs because some libraries are
not that well documented.
>> Yeah. So, niche libraries, not
well-known libraries, libraries that
have a smaller community, maybe an
academic community behind them. You
know, things like this,
they're going to be overlooked. Yeah.
And not to mention private libraries,
where there is no preexisting knowledge,
and you might not be able to
access that much knowledge about them.
>> So, what are the So, the problems I
think you know, I'm sure when you when
you say those types of, you know, issues
that agents and LLMs have, I'm sure all
of our listeners have you know, this
isn't news to them. They'll have
recognized They'll have seen this first
hand.
Not every single time, but you know,
every now and then they go, "Oh, yeah,
I'm coding and this happens."
Like people recognize it. Um how can we
make LLMs? What What's the solution? How
do we make LLMs more predictable
to be able to say, "Yes, I know where to
get that information from." How do we
get the the the answers, the evals,
highest? What did you learn? Well, it's
all about context, Simon. Of course it
is. Of course it is.
Um
So, what Tessa did
is uh we launched a something that we
call the Tessa Registry
that is a collection of more than 10,000
uh tiles. We call them tiles. I can see
Between you and I, we know what the
previous name was, and I know our
listeners maybe don't, but I could see I
could see your thought process there was
saying, "Don't say this. Don't say
this." But we're we're good. We got
through it. And I think I think despite
my despite my commentary there, I think
we got away with it.
Yes, um All right. Yes, so the tiles.
So, let me tell you what tiles are. So,
tiles are
uh they're collection of context. Hm. Um
And in this case, the 10,000 more than
10,000 tiles, they have context about
libraries, about different libraries,
and different versions of those
libraries. So, everything is versioned.
Um
And what we found with our evaluation
that's uh we previously talked about um
is that if we give the agent uh these
tiles for libraries that it's using in a
in a specific project, uh then it's uh
has better abstraction adherence. So,
remember the abstraction, the adherence
to those specific APIs for when using a
particular library. We observed that the
agent behaves better and is more likely
to use those abstractions correctly um
when it's uh uses the Tessa tiles. Yeah.
So, there's a couple of terms there.
Let's jump into tiles and then and then
uh adherence abstract No, abstraction
adherence.
Um I was just
adherence abstraction is kind of a thing
as well. No, not It's not Um but let's
start with tiles.
So I always I always love thinking of
tiles as almost like if you think about
a package like a
an NPM package or a Java package or
something like that. A collection a
grouping of source code and some
whatever it is some part part of your
application and it and it's typically
you know a package for that ecosystem. A
tile for me I always think of it in a
similar way. A tile is like a package
for your context
and of course there are three types of
context and I think the one we're going
to be talking about today is more about
the documentation. So there's
documentation, rules, and third is
commands I think, right? But that's kind
of a little bit more future thinking.
But the first two is is around
documentation which is describing
context that describes the best usage of
things like open source packages or or
beyond we can talk about private
packages and things like that as well.
Um
Rules are more descriptions of how you
want an agent to behave. So it's
actually a It's kind of like steering an
agent in a particular way or doing a
process in a particular way.
How do those two between documentation
and and kind of rules? How does an agent
use those two? Is is one more forced
upon it? One more kind of like optional
for it? What's the what's the way that
works? Interesting question. Yes. Um
The way I think about it is
um
documentation
is more about as you say more about
knowledge more about something that
it's not really behavioral. It's just
there. It's just facts.
And that is something that the agent can
reach for.
Right? So when when it doesn't know
something for example how to use a
library, it can it can reach for it. It
can ask a question
and go look for it.
Rules are more behavioral and they're
more about steering the agent.
And this is not something that it makes
sense for the agent. It can't It doesn't
really know how to reach for behavior
instructions. Do you Do you see what I
mean? It's more of a This is
encoded in me or you know this this has
been asked for me to do.
This has been asked for me to do.
So this is the slight subtlety there
and I don't think it's
Yeah, it's a bit subtle. I I don't think
it's like there's a mathematical formula
to to distinguish between those two but
but that's how I think about it. It's
reaching like can it actually reach?
Does it make sense for it to ask a
question about that piece of it? And
it's interesting cuz I think from the
volume of context that you would expect
in each of those,
a documentation
is it's a large knowledge base, right?
You you wouldn't expect to push all of
that into into a context whereas the a
set of rules you would expect yeah okay
this this is important. I need you to
follow this and you'd expect that to be
a much shorter kind of artifact so it
could probably keep that in context no
problem at all.
>> expect. Don't just expect. It actually
you know this getting ahead of ourselves
but actually one thing we've observed in
other experiments is that the longer the
the steering context is the the
the more you try to
ask the agent to behave certain ways the
less it's going to follow any of those
suggestions.
>> Okay.
Yeah, that's that's super interesting
actually. And it's like I always think
of it like kids. Like I always think of
it like kids where it's like LLMs are
kids basically
or maybe my kids are just acting like
LLMs. But
yeah, it's like it's like you want to
you want to give your kids knowledge to
be able to use at the right time at the
appropriate time when they decide to use
that knowledge. But there are certain
rules that you want to give them and you
always expect them to abide by those
rules. And so like that's a nice little
parallel in my mind that kind of that
kind of goes off. The second term that
we kind of like mentioned
was abstraction adherence. So you kind
of like mentioned the the levels of
abstraction and of course open source
and using open source
being a key level of abstraction that we
have over decades decades learned well
over over development. It's the
adherence for agents to use those.
That's that's abstraction adherence in
terms of what we're talking about here.
Um yes, it is about the agent adhering
to the abstractions that are available
by
by given given by some library or or
some private project or something like
that. So is the agent actually using
that abstraction? We have a very very
good example in the blog post which has
to do with
attention for the machine learning
community.
[Music]
Um PyTorch in the PyTorch library. So
PyTorch uh provides a one-liner
implementation of attention
but only after version 2.0 or something.
I don't I don't quite remember the
version.
Um
So if you ask an LLM that is trained
before this,
um it would generate attention from
scratch. Well, if you
uh you know if you if you provide
context for using torch,
it would
actually use the one-liner
implementation of attention. And that is
good for many reasons, right? That is
good because that implementation of
attention is optimized. It's much
faster. There are actually papers that
show that.
Um
so we we want that. And this is what
abstraction adherence is about. So
whether um the agent actually used the
intended abstraction or did it implement
it from scratch.
>> Right. Right. Okay.
Let's jump into the results but first
what do we talk about the scenarios?
What was the baseline I guess that we
kind of like worked out?
This is from scratch. What we want to
improve from. What did that look like?
>> The baseline
is just vanilla agent either Claude Code
or Cursor. These are the two agents that
we evaluated against
and just letting it do its thing, right?
So we know no restrictions. It can
search the web.
It can read the code if it wants to
but it's not explicitly
asked to do any of those things. So
>> Do I Do I dare ask which was better
between Claude Code and Cursor in the in
the results? What is that? Is that
setting fire underneath something I
don't need to set fire under? I can't
tell you.
>> Okay. Okay. That's fine. That's fine.
Check the blog post.
>> Check the blog post. Check the blog
post. It's really good. Check it
>> Okay. Cool. Cool.
So in terms of the key result in terms
of the next scenario what what would the
next scenario beyond the baseline be
that we tried? Yes. So we tried another
before getting to our approach we tried
another scenario which was explicitly
telling the agent to use
to read the source code of the package.
So including a folder within within the
project that has the source code and
telling the agent that it can read the
source code to check to double check
implementation, right?
We wanted to include this scenario
because we thought this is
this is kind of the not distilled not
specially curated version of tiles,
right? Cuz like you can imagine the
source code itself is a like a really
inflated style
cuz it has it has context.
>> Yeah.
It's just huge. It's just like massive
in terms of the volume. Yes. It's not
It's not optimized for reading by an
agent, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And of course not always
available, right? Like I come from Java
land where we have you know compiled
code the wonderful the wonderful world
of compiled code where
once you've compiled that code it's much
much harder I guess for the agent to be
able to to read that and understand that
because it doesn't really understand
bytecode as much as it does the the the
typical GitHub uh source. Exactly. And
everything would be also dependent on
the language and the frameworks you're
using. Yeah, absolutely. So we have the
baseline just Claude Code and and and
Cursor. We don't have access to the
source code and then beyond that And
then the third one is
using
the Tessel registry. Of course we
couldn't do this without Tessel, could
we? So So we have Tessel with the Tessel
registry and the Tessel registry
contains the context that describes the
open source packages. We have the
we have the the access having
agents have access to the full source
code and have to determine it themselves
but they have everything in front of
them. And then literally just training
data essentially with with the baseline.
What were the results?
The results were that using the Tessel
tiles on average showed 35% higher
abstraction adherence which was even
higher for newer libraries. So libraries
that were released in the last 3 years
there we saw 50% improvement of
>> 50% improvement of So 50% more likely to
use
the open source in the correct way the
criteria that was set of what we would
expect a developer really or or an agent
as well to use an open source library to
solve a problem that was given.
>> Yes.
Yeah, I think so as well. I think so as
well. And we saw a lot more interesting
things really. There there is so much
learnings from this experiment. Really
check the blog post.
It is very very interesting. But for
example we saw that the source code
setting that also performs well. Yeah.
But it was much slower and it took more
more turns.
I think it makes sense. It's because the
information is there. The context is
there but it's not optimized for usage.
It is it is messy. The agent needs to go
and search for it and grab all the time
and do a lot of turns and this slows
things down.
So And it And a turn here is that the
agent itself making
like making more and more decisions
about what it needs to do or is that
back and forth with the user?
Uh it's agent turns.
>> It's agent turns. So it's It steps the
steps that it takes in order to You got
you. to get there and and it's because
it has to
do a lot of more manual work in order to
>> lengthier and I guess therefore as a
result more expensive just in sheer
tokens that it's going to use. And
presumably is it is there with the
any context below as well because it
does all that or was that more done in I
guess a sub-agent?
That's a very good question.
I think cloud code in particular uses
sub-agents extensively. So we didn't
observe necessarily
anything like this.
But I can
I expect that for complex projects Mhm.
where I feel you know our our
tasks they were quite
small. They were It wasn't something
super complicated that needed to be done
especially if you're using the
abstractions correctly.
Um
but for larger projects that
kind of it's to implement a whole
feature or something of the sort.
I expect that there will be there will
be more problems Yeah. exactly this
because there will be so much more that
the agent will need to manually
discover. Yes. Yeah. Absolutely. Um in
terms of
you mentioned newer uh libraries or yeah
newer versions of libraries would would
cause a greater number of problems and
that's where you saw also kind of like
Tessel
succeed well. Which kind of makes sense
because you know less chance of it being
in the training data, fewer examples out
in the wild for for for the agents to
train on I guess. Um
what about super old legacy style
libraries where
you know I guess again similarly you're
going to have fewer people potentially
using the older versions but I'm sure
there's a ton of listeners that we have
whereby they have these dungeons of
legacy apps where they don't want to go
near them because they're
petrified of making changes and you know
we it's a it's a wonderful place for
agents to actually come in and start
understanding that code base but can we
trust the agent to equally make changes
in that code base? How did How did
legacy applications perform? Mhm.
Very good question. So what we observed
is that the baseline Yep. underperformed
for very old and very
relatively old and very new packages.
Mhm. So the graph looks like this. Yeah.
And I think that kind of makes sense
because probably the training data was
really focused towards
relatively new or libraries cuz that's
what's more used and and so on. Um but
they're not the newest most because
there is less information about them.
Mhm. Um so it checks out in my mind. Um
what we observed with when using Tessel
Tiles is that this was relatively
stable. So it did not depend so much how
old the or new the library is. It was a
relatively stable performance and higher
than that of the baseline in all cases.
Yeah. How about popularity of libraries
as well because obviously the most
popular libraries yeah they're probably
going to have a ton of of uh usage
examples in open source
uh repositories today. So much that all
of that will get into the training data
and the agents will have a good chance
maybe probably uh
getting versions and things like that
slightly wrong but it'll have a good
chance of actually getting close.
Um what about libraries that are lesser
known, lesser used and fewer examples in
the in in in the wild? How How did they
perform?
Yeah.
So
again kind of intuitively
what what we thought of intuitively we
saw in the data which is that the agents
would had a negative bias towards more
niche libraries. Niche here judged by
the number of forks on GitHub. So we
used that as a metric and then we could
see that the agents um the the baseline
Mhm.
just the agent um performed worse on
libraries with less forks. Yeah. Well
that wasn't the case for Tiles. Mhm. So
for Tiles we we saw a a big lift there.
Yeah. Um which was
Is it is for for using Tiles would you
say you can get those niche or
maybe even legacy versions up to a
similar kind of level as more popular
ones or is there still a gap between
more popular and
and more niche or or lesser used legacy
maybe
even using Tiles across both?
Yes absolutely. So we see that
niche libraries and popular libraries
when using Tessel Tiles at kind of at
the same level of performance. Wow. When
it comes to abstraction appearance.
Yeah. Yeah. Got you.
There's also a case study in the in the
report.
>> A very impressive
>> It's a very impressive case study and
it's with Is it LangGraph, right? That's
right. Yeah. LangGraph. Tell us a little
bit about well a little bit maybe about
LangGraph but again
what
what were the results with this case
study?
>> Yeah. So
that is it was a case study that uh one
of the other authors of the blog post
did Rob. So
um uh the idea there was to really deep
dive on this particular library and
in particular deep dive on new features.
>> Mhm. Features that
we knew that were introduced after the
training cut off of
um I think it was January?
I think it was solid 4.5 but
check the blog post. I think yeah I
think it's January January this year I
think. Yes. So
um
really looking at those features that
were that that were introduced
afterwards so that we know that they
were not part of the pre-training data
for the model. And presumably LangGraph
is a good example to choose because it's
had a number of releases fairly frequent
and as a result you see that change. So
it's a good example.
This is
all libraries will be like this but it's
a good example of when you see changes
fairly regularly it's something like
LangGraph. Yes. Yes exactly.
And what we saw there was that when
using
uh Tiles when using the LangGraph Tile
>> Yeah.
um
the agents performed 90% better to 90%
better on those new features. Yeah. Uh
which is
I mean yeah it's quite it's quite
impressive. I think
it makes sense because now we're giving
them the context and we're making it so
much easier for them.
>> Yeah. Uh
but also isn't it cool? Yeah. Like with
how much easier we can make it for them.
>> Yeah. Just by
and very simple to to actually We'll
talk about that in just a sec. One
burning question that I've got is
we mentioned a number of the problems
Yeah. like at the at the start of this
podcast episode uh with agents and how
they get certain things wrong.
Have we just fixed everything then or
are there still like issues? What's the
remaining issues I guess? Remaining
problems that even with these even with
using something like Tessel Tiles as
context um
what are the remaining problems that we
would should expect to see?
I think to me the biggest the biggest
problem I see is with
making the agent use this context
correctly. Right? So the steering of the
agent. How does How does the agent
actually know when to reach for that
context versus not to reach for that
context? This is This is a big question.
>> Mhm. And um I've seen it over and over
again. Steering is quite difficult to to
to do. Yeah. Uh and it's also something
that's quite difficult to evaluate which
makes things hard because we need to be
able as I mentioned at the beginning we
need to be able to measure something in
order to improve it. Mhm. Um
so
uh I think they're it's quite tricky
because a lot of
a lot of it is that we are at the mercy
of
whoever trains the models. We're at the
mercy of the big labs because that is
the biggest factor to how the agent
behaves. How does How does it know what
the next step is,
what training data they they put in
post-training in order to make it
behave this way.
>> Yeah. Um
of course there is
a lot we can do to control this. Mhm. Um
and and we have been very busy with that
at Tessel but it's a hard problem. Yeah.
Hard and very interesting problem.
Interesting.
How would you recommend someone get
started if they wanted to try the Tessel
Tiles themselves? Mhm.
Go on the website. Go on the website,
check out the Tessel registry. Um and
try it out. Anyone can try it. For
public libraries anyone can can go and
install Tessel and get going. So yeah
it's a it's a it's an MCP server that
you can kind of like you know add to
your agents then your agents can
effectively through MCP allow Tessel to
kind of you know
install that context, search for that
context and then you know provide that
steering so that the agent uses that
context for its requests. Um and it's
also a CLI if you wanted to use it like
that. From a from a producer point of
view
you can also create your own context as
well, right? And and if you have I think
we mentioned private private libraries
or if your open source library isn't you
isn't captured by our 10,000
tiles already, you can actually use that
you can actually create
a markdown like spec as as your context.
You can publish that into your private
registry and even make a request to make
that public in in the in the global
registry. So, there's a bunch you can
kind of like do there as as both a
consumer as a user as well as a someone
who wants to publish that context for
others to use for that using their
libraries or private
>> Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely. Amazing.
Maria, thank you so much first of all
for
sharing the work on the blog with with
your colleagues Rob and Max and Drew.
And thank you for coming on the podcast.
I really really had a great time having
a chat about this and doing a a deep
dive into this. Always love to
chatting Evals with Keith.
It won't be the last time, I'm sure. But
Maria, thank you so so much.
Thank you so much. Thank you for having
me.
>> Appreciate it.
And for those who want to read that
blog, check it out on the on the on the
Castle blog. But also we'll mention it
in the show notes as well. Thanks very
much for listening and we'll see you
next time. Bye for now.
[Music]